<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Building on Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/building/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Building on Dmytro&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 07:20:29 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/building/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Video Streaming Widget for iOS App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-video-streaming-widget-for-ios-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 07:20:29 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-video-streaming-widget-for-ios-app/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was exploring the idea of creating a YouTube-like widget for the lock screen on iOS devices. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy because most articles on the Internet discussed general implementations, such as for a coffee shop or a to-do list. Even when I found some similar versions, the project wouldn&amp;rsquo;t compile. I made the decision to approach it my way, so here&amp;rsquo;s what I found out:
Caveats After being stuck for two or more hours without understanding why, after tapping on a button, I wasn&#39;t able to receive a callback from it and the widget always opened the main iOS app, I realized that I forgot to add AppIntent - without it, you can&amp;rsquo;t handle actions for iOS 17.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Video Streaming iOS App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-video-streaming-ios-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 07:34:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-video-streaming-ios-app/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was looking for a way to add a video player to my iOS app that could be able to play remote videos.
Caveats Problem I found that you can&amp;rsquo;t open Vimeo or Youtube videos because of AVFoundationErrorDomain Code=-11850 &amp;quot;Operation Stopped&amp;quot; UserInfo={NSLocalizedFailureReason=The server is not correctly configured Domain=NSOSStatusErrorDomain Code=-12939 error. I don’t know exactly what this means, but I&amp;rsquo;m speculating it&amp;rsquo;s related to some protection.
Solution My solution was to find another video that is not related to those platforms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building movie recommendations using ML</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-movie-recommendations-using-ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 10:29:44 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-movie-recommendations-using-ml/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was wondering about how to create movie recommendations, so I decided to take a closer look and find out more about this topic. This is what I found:
First step: You need to create a JSON file with the data that you will use to train the model and define the parameters for training the model.
[ { &amp;#34;title&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Avatar&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;year&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;2009&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;rated&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;PG-13&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;released&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;18 Dec 2009&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;runtime&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;162 min&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;genre&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Action, Adventure, Fantasy&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;director&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;James Cameron&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;writer&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;James Cameron&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;actors&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Sam Worthington, Zoe Saldana, Sigourney Weaver, Stephen Lang&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;plot&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;A paraplegic marine dispatched to the moon Pandora on a unique mission becomes torn between following his orders and protecting the world he feels is his home.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Xcode project using Github Actions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-xcode-project-using-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 08:29:30 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-xcode-project-using-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering how to build an Xcode project using GitHub Actions, here are a few steps:
First, you need to create a .github/workflows folder with a CI.yml file inside your project directory. Next, you need to add configuration to the CI.yml file. name: CI on: push: branches: - main jobs: build: runs-on: macos-14 steps: - name: Checkout code uses: actions/checkout@v4 - name: Set up Xcode version run: sudo xcode-select -s /Applications/Xcode_15.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Xcode project using the CLI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-xcode-project-using-the-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 04:59:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-xcode-project-using-the-cli/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When you are working on different projects sometimes you need to use different IDE’s. You need to find a way to build a project in the fastest way.
One of such ways is by using the xcodebuild command Basic outline of the process Open Terminal: Open the Terminal application on your Mac. Navigate to Project Directory: Use the cd command to navigate to the directory containing your Xcode project. Run xcodebuild: Once you&amp;rsquo;re in the project directory, you can run xcodebuild with the appropriate parameters to build your project.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
