<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>SwiftUI on Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/swiftui/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SwiftUI on Dmytro&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 15:15:14 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/swiftui/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Group Chat using WebSockets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-group-chat-using-websockets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 15:15:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-group-chat-using-websockets/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I never had a chance to work with WebSockets, so I decided to take a look and create a group chat. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I discovered:
To be able to send and receive messages, you need to create an interface for communication between a server and your application. In my case, I chose sendMessage and receiveMessage methods. For the server-side, I chose Node.js. For the iOS application, I chose the Socket.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring visionOS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/exploring-visionos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 08:45:39 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/exploring-visionos/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I find myself fascinated by the idea of creating an app for visionOS where I could possibly display 3D AirPods that I like. Here are a few steps on how you can do the same:
First step The first step that you need to do is to create a visionOS project.
Second step The next step would be adding a 3D object to Reality Composer Pro and exporting it as a .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iOS AR App: Experience 3D Guitar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ios-ar-app-experience-3d-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:57:54 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ios-ar-app-experience-3d-guitar/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was searching for an AR implementation of a 3D guitar inside an iOS app. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I discovered:
First Step The first step is not related to building the app. Before that you need to create a project using the Reality Composer Pro app (you can find it through Spotlight search).
Second Step After that, you need to visit https://developer.apple.com/augmented-reality/quick-look/ and download one of the USDZ files. In my case, I chose the 3D guitar.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
