<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>SwiftUI on Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/swiftui/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SwiftUI on Dmytro&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.123.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 07:23:46 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/swiftui/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Animation - SwiftUI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/animation-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 07:23:46 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/animation-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was eager to learn about creating complex animations in SwiftUI. The few questions that were on my mind included what types of animations exist and what I can animate. Here is what I found:
Types of Animation SwiftUI has explicit and implicit animation types.
Implicit Animation: This is specified with the .animation() modifier. SwiftUI will animate changes in old and new values.
struct ImplicitAnimation: View { @State private var half = false @State private var dim = false var body: some View { Image(&amp;#34;tower&amp;#34;) .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing In-App Purchases to SwiftUI app using StoreKit 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/implementing-in-app-purchases-to-swiftui-app-using-storekit-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 07:57:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/implementing-in-app-purchases-to-swiftui-app-using-storekit-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was wondering how to add in-app purchases to my app. I chose non-consumable in-app purchase because you can pay one time for this item. Here are a few steps on how I did it.
First Step Set up In-App Purchases for your app in App Store Connect account or add a .storekit configuration file and start from there. If you&amp;rsquo;ve already set up In-App Purchases in your account, you can sync the StoreKit config with that data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Apple Pay in a SwiftUI app</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/implementing-apple-pay-in-a-swiftui-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 07:25:24 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/implementing-apple-pay-in-a-swiftui-app/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Sometime ago, I was working on a marketplace app, and I needed to add Apple Pay to make purchases more easily. Here are a few steps on how I did it: First Step You need to add Apple Pay capability to your project. You will need to Register a Merchant ID. I will skip this step; you can find info by following this link Setting up Apple Pay. Second Step You will need to import PassKit and create PKPaymentRequest to interact with PKPaymentAuthorizationController and PKPaymentAuthorizationControllerDelegate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration testing for SwiftUI views</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/integration-testing-for-swiftui-views/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 06:20:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/integration-testing-for-swiftui-views/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have been looking for information about implementation details of integration testing. I found a lot of information, but it was theoretical and all information looked the same. I did not find a meaningful example, so I tried to come up with my own definition and sample.
Integration testing means testing the behavior between modules or views to ensure they work as expected after user actions.
There are two ways of conducting integration testing: The first is by unit tests, where you try to test the flowing data between view models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UI testing SwiftUI views using XCTest Framework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ui-testing-swiftui-views-using-xctest-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 06:34:32 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ui-testing-swiftui-views-using-xctest-framework/</guid>
      <description>Introduction After spending some time developing my personal iOS app, I found myself in a position where I needed to add UI tests to my application. The reason behind this decision was the necessity to change the architecture to make it more scalable. However, this task proved to be challenging due to certain parts of the code being tightly coupled. The situation was quite frustrating. To address this problem, I decided to incorporate UI tests that could help identify issues during the refactoring process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Dynamic Island for Video Streaming App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-dynamic-island-for-video-streaming-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 07:35:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-dynamic-island-for-video-streaming-app/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was curious about how to add Dynamic Island and implement it into a Video Streaming App. Here are a few steps on how you can achieve this.
Caveats Debugging Dynamic Island can be a bit tricky; it only works when the main app is running. If you try to run it separately, you will encounter the error SendProcessControlEvent:toPid: encountered an error: Error Domain=com.apple.dt.deviceprocesscontrolservice Code=8 &amp;quot;Failed to show Widget&amp;quot;. The solution is to configure live activities and run them through the main app.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Video Streaming Widget for iOS App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-video-streaming-widget-for-ios-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 07:20:29 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-video-streaming-widget-for-ios-app/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was exploring the idea of creating a YouTube-like widget for the lock screen on iOS devices. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy because most articles on the Internet discussed general implementations, such as for a coffee shop or a to-do list. Even when I found some similar versions, the project wouldn&amp;rsquo;t compile. I made the decision to approach it my way, so here&amp;rsquo;s what I found out:
Caveats After being stuck for two or more hours without understanding why, after tapping on a button, I wasn&#39;t able to receive a callback from it and the widget always opened the main iOS app, I realized that I forgot to add AppIntent - without it, you can&amp;rsquo;t handle actions for iOS 17.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Video Streaming iOS App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-video-streaming-ios-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 07:34:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-video-streaming-ios-app/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was looking for a way to add a video player to my iOS app that could be able to play remote videos.
Caveats Problem I found that you can&amp;rsquo;t open Vimeo or Youtube videos because of AVFoundationErrorDomain Code=-11850 &amp;quot;Operation Stopped&amp;quot; UserInfo={NSLocalizedFailureReason=The server is not correctly configured Domain=NSOSStatusErrorDomain Code=-12939 error. I don’t know exactly what this means, but I&amp;rsquo;m speculating it&amp;rsquo;s related to some protection.
Solution My solution was to find another video that is not related to those platforms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Group Chat using WebSockets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-group-chat-using-websockets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 15:15:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-group-chat-using-websockets/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I never had a chance to work with WebSockets, so I decided to take a look and create a group chat. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I discovered:
To be able to send and receive messages, you need to create an interface for communication between a server and your application. In my case, I chose sendMessage and receiveMessage methods. For the server-side, I chose Node.js. For the iOS application, I chose the Socket.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring visionOS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/exploring-visionos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 08:45:39 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/exploring-visionos/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I find myself fascinated by the idea of creating an app for visionOS where I could possibly display 3D AirPods that I like. Here are a few steps on how you can do the same:
First step The first step that you need to do is to create a visionOS project.
Second step The next step would be adding a 3D object to Reality Composer Pro and exporting it as a .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iOS AR App: Experience 3D Guitar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ios-ar-app-experience-3d-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:57:54 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ios-ar-app-experience-3d-guitar/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was searching for an AR implementation of a 3D guitar inside an iOS app. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I discovered:
First Step The first step is not related to building the app. Before that you need to create a project using the Reality Composer Pro app (you can find it through Spotlight search).
Second Step After that, you need to visit https://developer.apple.com/augmented-reality/quick-look/ and download one of the USDZ files. In my case, I chose the 3D guitar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building movie recommendations using ML</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-movie-recommendations-using-ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 10:29:44 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-movie-recommendations-using-ml/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was wondering about how to create movie recommendations, so I decided to take a closer look and find out more about this topic. This is what I found:
First step: You need to create a JSON file with the data that you will use to train the model and define the parameters for training the model.
[ { &amp;#34;title&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Avatar&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;year&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;2009&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;rated&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;PG-13&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;released&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;18 Dec 2009&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;runtime&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;162 min&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;genre&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Action, Adventure, Fantasy&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;director&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;James Cameron&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;writer&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;James Cameron&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;actors&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Sam Worthington, Zoe Saldana, Sigourney Weaver, Stephen Lang&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;plot&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;A paraplegic marine dispatched to the moon Pandora on a unique mission becomes torn between following his orders and protecting the world he feels is his home.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
