<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dmytro&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 04:59:38 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to build an Xcode project using the CLI?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 04:59:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When you are working on different projects sometimes you need to use different IDE’s. You need to find a way to build a project in the fastest way.
One of such ways is by using the xcodebuild command Basic outline of the process Open Terminal: Open the Terminal application on your Mac. Navigate to Project Directory: Use the cd command to navigate to the directory containing your Xcode project. Run xcodebuild: Once you&amp;rsquo;re in the project directory, you can run xcodebuild with the appropriate parameters to build your project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Visitor Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 08:01:22 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-1/</guid>
      <description>In this article: What is a Visitor Pattern? What problems does it solve? Real-world code example What is a Visitor Pattern? The Visitor Pattern helps add new capabilities to a composite of objects.
Source
What problems does it solve? The Visitor Pattern helps solve following problems:
Separation of Concerns: The Visitor Pattern separates algorithms from the objects on which they operate. This allows for clean code organization by keeping algorithms and operations separate from the data structures they operate on.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
