<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dmytro&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 04:59:38 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to build an Xcode project using the CLI?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 04:59:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When you are working on different projects sometimes you need to use different IDE’s. You need to find a way to build a project in the fastest way.
One of such ways is by using the xcodebuild command Basic outline of the process Open Terminal: Open the Terminal application on your Mac. Navigate to Project Directory: Use the cd command to navigate to the directory containing your Xcode project. Run xcodebuild: Once you&amp;rsquo;re in the project directory, you can run xcodebuild with the appropriate parameters to build your project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Visitor Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 08:01:22 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-1/</guid>
      <description>In this article: What is a Visitor Pattern? What problems does it solve? Real-world code example What is a Visitor Pattern? The Visitor Pattern helps add new capabilities to a composite of objects.
Source
What problems does it solve? The Visitor Pattern helps solve following problems:
Separation of Concerns: The Visitor Pattern separates algorithms from the objects on which they operate. This allows for clean code organization by keeping algorithms and operations separate from the data structures they operate on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Information about me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>E-commerce Proficient in developing marketplace and utility management apps, capable of creating e-commerce platforms with features like product catalogs, user authentication, payment gateways, and order management systems.
Healthcare Skilled in healthcare app development, with experience in building Glucose Tracker and COVID-19 tracking applications. Capable of developing apps for health metric monitoring, telemedicine, medication management, and wellness tracking.
Finance Experienced in utility management and currency-related projects, able to create personal finance management apps, budgeting tools, and investment trackers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ios-app-maintenance-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ios-app-maintenance-service/</guid>
      <description>iOS App Maintenance Service This service is designed to improve your app’s stability, leading to more 5-star ratings and increased user satisfaction.
Is This Service Right for You? Here are a few questions for you:
Are you tired of getting negative app reviews due to bugs and crashes? Feel frustrated by your app’s low search rank and disappointing download numbers? Always worried about your app’s sudden breakdowns post-iOS updates? Struggling to find a reliable developer when your app needs quick fixes?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
