<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dmytro&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 13:46:03 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Archiving Xcode project using the CLI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 13:46:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-6/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When you are working on different projects sometimes you need to use different IDE’s. You need to find a way to archive a project in the fastest way.
One of such ways is by using the xcodebuild archive command Basic outline of the process Open Terminal: Open the Terminal application on your Mac. Navigate to Project Directory: Use the cd command to navigate to the directory containing your Xcode project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing Xcode project using the CLI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 03:20:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-3/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When you are working on different projects sometimes you need to use different IDE’s. You need to find a way to test a project in the fastest way.
One of such ways is by using the xcodebuild command Basic outline of the process Open Terminal: Open the Terminal application on your Mac. Navigate to Project Directory: Use the cd command to navigate to the directory containing your Xcode project. Run xcodebuild: Once you&amp;rsquo;re in the project directory, you can run xcodebuild with the appropriate parameters to build your project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Xcode project using the CLI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 04:59:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When you are working on different projects sometimes you need to use different IDE’s. You need to find a way to build a project in the fastest way.
One of such ways is by using the xcodebuild command Basic outline of the process Open Terminal: Open the Terminal application on your Mac. Navigate to Project Directory: Use the cd command to navigate to the directory containing your Xcode project. Run xcodebuild: Once you&amp;rsquo;re in the project directory, you can run xcodebuild with the appropriate parameters to build your project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Visitor Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 08:01:22 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-1/</guid>
      <description>In this article: What is a Visitor Pattern? What problems does it solve? Real-world code example What is a Visitor Pattern? The Visitor Pattern helps add new capabilities to a composite of objects.
Source
What problems does it solve? The Visitor Pattern helps solve following problems:
Separation of Concerns: The Visitor Pattern separates algorithms from the objects on which they operate. This allows for clean code organization by keeping algorithms and operations separate from the data structures they operate on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is “reference type” in Swift?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-5/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In Swift, classes, closures, and actors all reference types.
&amp;lsquo;Reference type’ is instance that shares a single copy of data.
Assigning a reference type to a constant or variable, or passing it into a function or method, it is always a reference to a shared instance that is assigned or passed in.
Example You can pass your property value by sharing the same address in memory.
// Reference type example class Storage { var data = “data-example” } var storage = Storage() print(&amp;#34;\(storage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let’s talk about Composable Architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-4/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Composable Architecture (TCA) uses a unidirectional data flow (UDF). UDF is a design pattern where data and events move consistently and predictably. In UDF, data can only be transferred to other application parts in one way.
In TCA, the only way to mutate the state is by sending actions to a runtime store. The runtime store holds the entire app’s business logic and mutates the state inside.
UDF can reduce data inconsistencies because of the single source of truth for the application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Information about me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>E-commerce Proficient in developing marketplace and utility management apps, capable of creating e-commerce platforms with features like product catalogs, user authentication, payment gateways, and order management systems.
Healthcare Skilled in healthcare app development, with experience in building Glucose Tracker and COVID-19 tracking applications. Capable of developing apps for health metric monitoring, telemedicine, medication management, and wellness tracking.
Finance Experienced in utility management and currency-related projects, able to create personal finance management apps, budgeting tools, and investment trackers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ios-app-maintenance-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ios-app-maintenance-service/</guid>
      <description>iOS App Maintenance Service This service is designed to improve your app’s stability, leading to more 5-star ratings and increased user satisfaction.
Is This Service Right for You? Here are a few questions for you:
Are you tired of getting negative app reviews due to bugs and crashes? Feel frustrated by your app’s low search rank and disappointing download numbers? Always worried about your app’s sudden breakdowns post-iOS updates? Struggling to find a reliable developer when your app needs quick fixes?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thank You</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>Thank You Thank you for your interest in this course! Your enthusiasm means a lot to me. Currently, I&#39;m in the testing phase for this idea. If there&#39;s significant interest from individuals like you, I&#39;ll move forward with creating the course. If you&#39;d like to stay updated on its progress, please feel free to drop me an email. Your support is truly appreciated!
If you have any questions or want updates, please email me at dmytro.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
