<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Implementing on Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/implementing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Implementing on Dmytro&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.123.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 07:57:51 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/implementing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implementing In-App Purchases to SwiftUI app using StoreKit 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/implementing-in-app-purchases-to-swiftui-app-using-storekit-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 07:57:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/implementing-in-app-purchases-to-swiftui-app-using-storekit-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was wondering how to add in-app purchases to my app. I chose non-consumable in-app purchase because you can pay one time for this item. Here are a few steps on how I did it.
First Step Set up In-App Purchases for your app in App Store Connect account or add a .storekit configuration file and start from there. If you&amp;rsquo;ve already set up In-App Purchases in your account, you can sync the StoreKit config with that data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Apple Pay in a SwiftUI app</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/implementing-apple-pay-in-a-swiftui-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 07:25:24 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/implementing-apple-pay-in-a-swiftui-app/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Sometime ago, I was working on a marketplace app, and I needed to add Apple Pay to make purchases more easily. Here are a few steps on how I did it: First Step You need to add Apple Pay capability to your project. You will need to Register a Merchant ID. I will skip this step; you can find info by following this link Setting up Apple Pay. Second Step You will need to import PassKit and create PKPaymentRequest to interact with PKPaymentAuthorizationController and PKPaymentAuthorizationControllerDelegate.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
