<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Streaming on Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/streaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Streaming on Dmytro&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dmytro&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 07:35:52 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/streaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Dynamic Island for Video Streaming App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-dynamic-island-for-video-streaming-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 07:35:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-dynamic-island-for-video-streaming-app/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was curious about how to add Dynamic Island and implement it into a Video Streaming App. Here are a few steps on how you can achieve this.
Caveats Debugging Dynamic Island can be a bit tricky; it only works when the main app is running. If you try to run it separately, you will encounter the error SendProcessControlEvent:toPid: encountered an error: Error Domain=com.apple.dt.deviceprocesscontrolservice Code=8 &amp;quot;Failed to show Widget&amp;quot;. The solution is to configure live activities and run them through the main app.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Video Streaming Widget for iOS App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-video-streaming-widget-for-ios-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 07:20:29 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-video-streaming-widget-for-ios-app/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was exploring the idea of creating a YouTube-like widget for the lock screen on iOS devices. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy because most articles on the Internet discussed general implementations, such as for a coffee shop or a to-do list. Even when I found some similar versions, the project wouldn&amp;rsquo;t compile. I made the decision to approach it my way, so here&amp;rsquo;s what I found out:
Caveats After being stuck for two or more hours without understanding why, after tapping on a button, I wasn&#39;t able to receive a callback from it and the widget always opened the main iOS app, I realized that I forgot to add AppIntent - without it, you can&amp;rsquo;t handle actions for iOS 17.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Video Streaming iOS App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-video-streaming-ios-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 07:34:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-video-streaming-ios-app/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was looking for a way to add a video player to my iOS app that could be able to play remote videos.
Caveats Problem I found that you can&amp;rsquo;t open Vimeo or Youtube videos because of AVFoundationErrorDomain Code=-11850 &amp;quot;Operation Stopped&amp;quot; UserInfo={NSLocalizedFailureReason=The server is not correctly configured Domain=NSOSStatusErrorDomain Code=-12939 error. I don’t know exactly what this means, but I&amp;rsquo;m speculating it&amp;rsquo;s related to some protection.
Solution My solution was to find another video that is not related to those platforms.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
